Well, it's uh February 2nd, 2026. Uh
6:02 p.m. March. And I'm reading the
wrong script. Okay.
Good evening. It's 6:02 p.m. on March
2nd, 2026.
I'd like to call this evening's uh City
of Cheyenne Planning Commission to
order. Will staff please call roll.
>> Megan Connor
>> present remotely.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Luan Olson
>> here remotely.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
Bob Mia here.
Tony Leard
Wigum present.
Mr. Chair, we do have a quorum. Okay.
Thank you.
Well, the first or second order of
business is uh approval agenda and and
minutes.
Uh, do we have any changes to the agenda
as presented?
Okay.
And I will accept a a motion on the
minutes for the February 2nd, 2026
meeting.
>> So moved.
>> All second.
>> Okay, we've got a uh a motion to approve
uh by Bob Ma, second by Lonnie Olsen.
Um, are there any changes or amendments
to the to the minutes requested?
Hearing none.
All in favor? This is just voice vote. I
>> I
>> Okay.
Oppose. Same sign.
Motion carries. Any
disclosures of conflicts or anything for
any of the items on the agenda tonight?
Okay. Will staff please read item A into
the record.
Item A,
PUDC-26-7
uh 2900 Central Avenue zone change.
>> Will the applicant please
present your proposal?
>> Chairman, Planning Commission members
Brad Emmens, AVI. Um I am going to speak
on this item and the next item because
it kind of makes more sense when they're
going at the same time. But before you
is a zone change from MR to NR2. Um this
is an existing
uh looks like a townhouse complex, but
currently it's actually all on one lot.
So it's currently acting as apartments.
Uh the applicant and owner um 2900
Central LL Avenue LLC is looking to
convert it to town houses using the
cottage lot section so that they can
sell these individually. um they can if
we get the zone change in the platting,
it allows the purchasers of the property
to get 30-year fixed regular mortgages
on the property. If we were to condo
them, um which is the other option, you
end up with a 20-year a variable rate
mortgage. So, um trying to make it more
uh or a better project for the future
purchasers of the project by allowing
them to get 30-year fixed mortgages on
the property. Um if this project once
this is done will still require a site
plan. So we're not completely done when
we get the uh zone change and plat. Um
we will be submitting that site plan
shortly uh to go through all the rest of
the cottage lot uh criteria. Happy to
answer any questions of the commission.
>> Thank you. Any of the commissioners have
questions? Commissioner,
you have an HOA that's going to watch
over the
>> Mr. Chairman through you. One of the
conditions of the things is will be a
association and um also you have to have
a common uh owned lot. So, the open
space, the front yards, uh the
outdoor space between the back of the
units and the garages will all be
controlled by that owner, that group.
And they'll all actually in this case
have a ownership in that so that it will
keep it funded through that that system
or that they all will include their
property taxes of the open space all go
through since they have undivided
interest in that open space. Any
of the Any further questions?
Any questions from the commissioners
participating via Zoom?
Hearing none, will staff please present
your report?
>> And Mr. Chair, I'd just like to note
that uh Commissioner Leard is online. I
just didn't realize it was him due to
the different name on Zoom, but I did
ask in chat and he is online.
>> So, for the record, we have five
commissioners present. Correct. Okay.
Thank you.
>> All right. For the record, Conorway
Planning and Development Department, uh,
this project is a zone change. It's
located northwest of the intersection of
East 29th Street and Central Avenue.
The current zoning is medium density
residential and on the future land use
map it is urban residential.
The surrounding area is medium density.
Uh there is some MUB to the south um
east. You do have uh public zoning to
the south and a little bit to the east
as well and then the rest is MR.
The applicant is requesting a zone
change to NR2, which is neighborhood
residential uh medium density.
The NR2 does allow for cottage lots as a
use by right. Um in the MR zone, it
would be a conditional use. So I guess
without the zone change, they could go
for that to the board of adjustment
rather than coming to the commissioners
for a zone change. But
um having to do a plat
coming here as well with the zone change
on top of that is a little bit easier.
Also, this area um
does kind of conform to the NR2 zone. Um
NR2 basically any of the NR zones kind
of looked at
basically restricting parking and access
to basically the rear off of alleys. Um
most of the older neighborhoods are
usually rear access from alleys.
Same thing with this project. Um they've
got the garages off the alleys, so the
NR2 does restrict basically access to
that. Um so it's not changing basically
how the lot already operates. Most of
the again, most of the neighborhood is
already this way. So NR2 would actually
fit for a lot of the neighborhood rather
than just the single lot.
Um
again, cottage lots is the use that
they're looking at due to the next item
on the agenda, which is the plat. uh
cottage lots is permitted in the NR2. Um
so it would allow them basically to have
the lot configuration that they're
proposing to allow each individual
existing unit to be on its own lot so
that it's a fee simple lot and can be
sold off um individually rather than
this be considered one multif family
parcel.
through staff's review. Um, we do find
that it meets all the review criteria
and we would recommend approval of this
zone change 10R2. And with that, I'm
available for any questions.
Commissioners, any questions for staff?
Any of the uh commissioners
participating via Zoom have questions
for staff?
Okay, I guess I have a question and I
guess it's predictable. Uh, would staff
please address any spots zoning analysis
that occurred since I do not see any NR2
adjacent zoning.
>> Mr. Chair, um staff would consider this
spot zoning. It is a residential zone um
just like the surrounding residential
zone. It's just a different type of
residential zone. So we have both we
have six residential zone districts. So
we do have the LR, MR, HR, NR1, NR2,
NR3. All those are residential zones. Uh
the urban residential future land use
map designation would expect that any of
those residential zones would work for
um an urban basically the urban
residential future land use designation.
So when SNAP reviews these residential
zone changes, um we don't really
consider them spot zoning as the area is
already residential. It's just turning
it to another residential zone. And
again, we also looked at the fact that
really we could go back and reszone this
entire neighborhood to NR2. And it would
make sense um because again NR2 looks
more at kind of smaller lots uh
condensed urban development and also
rear loaded access for properties which
is much of the avenues area or even the
this area which is I guess not depends
how you look at the avenues if you
consider south of Persian avenues or
not. Um but similar development in the
area where it was predominantly rear
loaded access smaller lots. So we don't
really consider this as staff to be spot
zoning because it is just another
residential zone district.
>> Would it be fair to say that this zoning
is maybe even more reflective of of the
existing development than the MR zone?
>> Mr. through you. I believe staff would
agree with that. That is and I would
like to add that I think that was the
thought back when the UDC was also being
developed is technically they should
have gone back through and reszoned
areas of the city to add the NR zones
into various locations but never did. Um
so the NR zone would probably be more
reflective of what is currently in this
area than the existing MR.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Any of the other commissioners have
questions for staff
hearing? None.
Is there any member of the public who
would like to
comment on this item?
Public comment going one once. Public
comment going twice, three times. Public
comment is closed.
Commissioners, any comments or
is he ready to offer a offer a motion
or did I mess up? Do I need to offer to
allow the applicant to
>> You're good to respond. Okay.
>> We already did public comment.
>> You can offer, but it's not a necessary
thing right Okay,
I'm waiting for either comments or a
motion.
>> I will move I move to approve the
resoning of 2900 Central Avenue town
homes to NR2 neighborhood residential
medium density as shown in the attached
zone change map, noting that the project
meets the review criteria for approval.
>> I've got a motion. Do I have a second?
Was that Commissioner Olsson?
>> Yeah,
it's
>> been moved by
Commissioner M and seconded by
Commissioner Olsen.
Discussion from the commission.
Amendments to the motion.
Hearing none, will staff please call
roll.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Yes.
Sony alert.
Tony, if you are on, you do need to
unmute. Just as an FYI.
>> Okay. Can you hear me now?
>> Yes.
>> I vote yes.
Lonnie Olsson
>> I
Bob
>> Math
>> I
>> Mr. Chair that motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you. And for the record, can
you please read item B
into the record?
>> Item B, PDC-26-8
2900 Central Avenue expedited plat.
>> Okay. Thank you. Would the applicant
like to supplement your comments or your
presentation?
>> Um, Mr. Chairman, through you again,
Brad Amens, I did uh receive one phone
call and went through the project with
them and they were okay with it. So,
just wanted to pass that along that I
did get one public comment on the
project.
>> Thank you,
staff. And I guess any questions for the
for the applicant from the commission
before we move on to staff report.
Staff report please.
Chair members commission counterway
planning and development department.
This plat is same location as the
previous zone change. Um so northwest of
the intersection of East 29th and
Central Avenue. Again, the property is
uh currently zoned MR and it is
surrounded by MR and then urban
residential on the future land use map.
Uh the applicant is proposing replatting
this one parcel. Uh it's about.5 acres
into 17 lots for fee simple ownership of
the townhouse units. So this is an
existing development. Um it's basically
multif family at this point, but it's
built in a townhouse style. Um, so this
plat would divide each of the units onto
their own property that would allow them
to basically be sold off and then an HOA
would handle the common lot.
Um, with this plat, this would end up
being considered cottage lots, which
again is permitted in that NR2 zone.
Otherwise, it would require a
conditional use in the MR. And then it
does require a site plan to basically
show the common space um and the
amenities for that.
Through the review staff uh does
recommend approval um of this expedited
plat.
I would like to note there was a
condition in the staff report and that
was to add the block number to the face
of the plat that has been done. Uh we
did receive resubmitt and that block
number is on there. So that's no longer
needed in the motion. Um so I do have
the correct motion up on the screen
which is basically if you just cut off
anything after governing body. Uh so
there is no condition. So staff does
recommend approval without that
condition. And I stand for any
questions.
Okay.
>> Thank you. Any questions from the
commission for staff?
Hearing none. Is Is Commissioner Lair
able to speak or attempting to speak?
>> Uh I'm I am able, I think, but I'm not
attempting to.
>> Okay. Thank you. Just just checking. Um
just a quick question. You mentioned an
HOA and a common lot. would you please
educate us sort of the public about that
what's going on there?
>> So Mr. Chair through you um with plats
of this nature that create a common lot
there is a requirement uh for platting
that some sort of documentation be
provided of how that common lot is going
to be maintained. In this case we were
provided a draft kind of HOA document uh
for that common lot. So each ownership
or basically each owner will be part of
that HOA that will then work to maintain
that common open space. Um but that is a
requirement of platting. They do have to
show and provide some sort of
documentation as to how that common
space will be um basically kept.
>> And as I understand it looks like that's
lot 17 and basically the parking lot
>> Mr. Chair through you. So that would be
lot 17. Um there is actually no parking
lot. There's just the garages with
driveway up to them. The rest of it
would just be open space, green area. Um
but again, all that will also be
documented with a site plan. Okay. Which
is basically existing conditions.
Okay. Thank you.
Hearing no other questions from or any
other questions from the commission
hearing. None. Is there any member of
the public who is here who wishes to
comment on this item? Going once, going
twice. Public comment is closed
and
the chair is looking for a motion.
Um, is there any way up the motion?
Uh, chair.
>> Uh, yes. Commissioner Leairard Olsson.
>> Uh, I move to approve the 2900 Central
Avenue town homes preliminary plat
advancing the final plat to the
governing body.
>> Thank you. I've got a motion. Is there a
second?
>> Second.
Okay. Second by Commissioner Ma.
Any discussion by the commission
regarding the motion that's on the table
hearing? None.
Will staff please call roll.
>> Lonnie Olsson.
>> I.
>> Megan Connor.
>> I
Mathia.
>> I.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Mr. Chair. That motion passes.
Okay. Thank you.
Will staff please read item C into the
record.
>> Item C, PUDC-26-25,
Harmony Valley Apartments Zoning Map
Amendment.
Chair to John Sers with representing
True Grit Land Development. This
particular piece of land already has a
site plan submitted to the city I think
over a year and a half ago. We've
corrected it. It's been revised and
resubmitted recently. Um, in order to do
this, we looked at uh with this with
staff and we're taking it out of the PUD
like we did in uh Harmony Valley Fifth,
which we'll explain on the next zone
change. Um, this piece particularly was
to go ahead and get it to match in. So,
we hit the parking in the alley or the
uh layout of the buildings as so forth
on this particular property. Uh,
basically, it just took it to where uh
we were going to have to do office space
and so forth. And by the NR3, it didn't
require it from the PUD. The PUD was
done, and don't quote me, but I want to
say Connor, you're gonna have to help me
or Seth because I didn't do it, but it
was way back in 2020, I believe, and the
PUD was based on less stringent uh rules
at the time than the city had for the
particular zoning areas. So, the owner
at the time had chose to do the PUD.
Since working through the PUD and city
staff has modified a lot of the zoning
in the area, we went ahead and trying to
move this to NR3 simply just to get it
back into compliance with less of the
restrictions that were heavily more
impacted on the PUD than in the current
NR3. Uh we did this exact same situation
uh and we'll explain further, but over
off of York uh we went through when we
did Harmony Valley Fifth Filing in order
to make the cottage lots and so forth,
we went ahead and uh changed it out of
the PUD to make the requirements so we
could do alley loads on attached
dwellings over there. So I'm happy to
address any comments. Uh this site plan
is at the city but we are moving with
this piece and then hopefully an
expedited plat either this next middle
or the following one for that one that
would take into account the common open
space and then each particular building.
>> Okay. Uh, commission. Does do any of the
commissioners have questions for the
applicant?
Hearing none, I I've got a question.
Um, what
specific
regulation did you have in your PUD
that you are being able to get out of by
pulling
this parcel out of the PUD and and going
back to a a city zone.
>> Mr. Chair, through you uh it modified
the number of units available. So by
taking it out of the PUD and going back
to the NR3, we only gained eight units
out of this particular unit plus the
availability for garages on the site and
no office or man office manager on site.
And that's it.
I think there was a couple more, but I I
didn't bring that forward with us today.
Any
other questions from the commission?
Okay, that uh staff, please read present
your report.
>> Okay.
>> Morgan Dennis, planning and development.
Um, this is a zone a zone change request
for lot one, block one, Harmony Valley
fourth filing from Harmony Valley,
Harmony Valley PUB to NR3 zone district.
The surrounding
zoning for this parcel is MR to the
north, Harmony Valley PUD to the east,
county light industrial to the west, and
county land use to the south that
contains single family residential
dwellings.
The future land use map designates this
area as mixeduse commercial. This
designation supports more commercial or
live work developments that could be
activity centers. The res residential
developments are typically secondary in
this designation and should be
highdensity developments. This site is
also located at the intersection of
South Parley Boulevard and West College
Drive. to art arterial arterial
streets. Traffic from these streets
could be higher than desired in
residential areas.
NR3 zone is intended to be used for
highdensity urban residential uses with
regulations to protect neighborhood
character and residential use of the
land. Application of this use not near a
planned activity centers or
concentrations of density without
walking access to non-residential uses
and quality urban amenities should be
avoided due to top due to topography and
current developmental
patterns. There are no true there it is
not a walkable area at this time. The
Harmony Valley PUD outlines this area as
high density residential. This
designation allows for intense
development commercial and highdensity
residential permitted per the PUB then
than the proposed zone allows for. The
more optimal zone for this area is the
MUB mixed use business zone. This zone
accomplishes the future land use map
objectives as it allows commercial and
highdensity residential development.
This corridor lacks commercial zoning as
there is a lot of residential
development in the area. MUB is a
combination of NR3 and the NB zone which
allow for NR3 lot types and residential
design standards.
The comprehensive plan does support
flexibility to adjust to market demands
and supports developmental
of housing to meet these demands.
While the NR3 zone will limit overall
allowable development action in this
area, adding housing units will be
meeting a market and developmental
demands. With that, staff recommends
approval of the zone change from Harmony
Valley PUB to NR3.
I stand for questions.
>> Mr. Chairman, through you. I am com
concerned about the fact that this given
the location of this it would be perfect
or pretty pretty good location for some
kind of commercial or business activity
and we're now converting it into
residential and I just wonder where is
the nearest business type or commercial
activity.
>> Uh Mr. chair through you. The nearest
commercial corridor in this area is
along I believe Gley Highway. Is that
the highway in that area? Yeah, it would
be over in that area.
>> Chair through you to Commissioner Matia.
And in addition regarding the commercial
at that area, that area is very limited
in future growth uh with residential. So
it would be kind of on the fringe. So in
looking at the analysis here for
modifying where commercial would go,
we'd really like to see that focus more
in areas where there is housing that is
surrounding it. At that parsley and
college drive area, you really have just
the housing to the northwest and
northeast.
Northeast and southeast. The northwest
is primarily um industrial and then it
tapers off quickly as more industry does
start to pop up as you head further to
the west.
>> Mr. Chair through you.
>> So you're counting housetops, rooftops,
saying that there's not enough
>> rooftops there to support.
>> Chair through you too, Commissioner Mia.
That's correct. Yes.
>> Um sta um I've got a question for uh for
staff. Um, thinking about the PUD that
was in place before, does removal of
this parcel, and I guess I'll have the
same question on on the next item, does
removal of this parcel from the PUD in
any way undermine the the philosophy
behind the PUD or the the integrity of
of the PUD
that was supposed to be a little more
comprehensive when it was adopted.
Mr. Chair, Seth Lloyd, Planning and
Development Department. Um, the PUD
definitely had a vision for the area um
as a as a region. Um but at the same
time the PUD's
um essential characteristics are based
on the street type and the park. Um so
the street type down there has um
monolithic or curved gutter sidewalk
attached whereas the city standard was
detached uh sidewalks. Um this area
doesn't really have much in the way of
street adjacent and the street that is
adjacent is already built. And then the
park is also already built. So I don't
believe this would detract from the
portions of the PUD that have been
developed um because they do have that
street section in those residential
single single unit residential areas and
they do have that park that has been um
developed in that area. Um, that also
being said, um, PUDs often serve special
purposes, and if those special ser
purposes aren't needed or necessary, um,
then it would be better to have standard
city zoning. Um, to be honest, staff is
looking at some PUDS, especially along
Bell Range, um, where whatever purpose
they served back in the day, they don't
really have that purpose anymore. And
so, we'd look to change those PUDs to
standard zoning.
>> Okay. Thank you. And a a follow-up
question, does this in any way affect
any HOA that may have existed as part of
the PUD, if one existed?
>> Mr. Chair, it's my understanding there
does there is an HOA that is uh involved
with Harmony Valley. Um I would let the
applicant answer the question as to
whether or not the HOA would extend to
this parcel or not.
>> Okay,
we'll do that a little later.
Uh, do any other commissioners have
questions about this for staff?
>> Mr. Chair, through you, Mrs. Tony.
>> Thank you.
>> Go ahead.
>> I guess I uh
my question is more along the lines of
it doesn't seem to align now with the uh
future land use plan.
And I remember
one of the early items we had in the
commission when I became a member a
couple years ago was I think it was the
uh Edwards development around story and
Converse. We actually had an action to
change the future land use map. Is that
does staff feel that that's appropriate
or do they think this aligns well
enough?
>> Staff
Mr. Chair, members of the planning
commission, certainly the MUB zoning
would be a more optimal zone in this
location that would align with future
land use map precisely. Um the future
land use map does s um
recommend commercial mixed with
high-intensity residential and by zoning
MUB that would allow for the mix to
continue whereas zoning NR3 does not
allow for the mix with commercial. Um,
however, MUB zoning would also allow uh
apartments or multif family development
as a use by right. Um, certainly we as
staff, we would prefer to see the MUB
zone at this location over the NR3 zone.
Um, but at the end of the day, the MUB
zone would also allow apartments. Um,
and we also have urban residential
designations sandwiching this parcel to
the north and south. Um, and the future
land use map is not supposed to be a
second zoning map. It's kind of
something you look at with blurred lines
or fuzzy lines as it were. Um so this
this parcel um is kind of on the edge of
that m that future land use designation.
Um certainly a case could be made that
MUB, you know, this zone should really
be MUB as opposed to NR3, but staff
thinks MU NR3 is acceptable for this
location.
Commissioner Larair, was that adequate?
Do you have any follow-up questions?
>> Uh, no. I think I understand.
>> Okay. Uh, any of the other commissioners
in Zoom land have questions for staff?
Okay. Hearing none.
Um,
is there any member of the public who is
here? We'll I'll finish with you. Um, is
there any member of the public who is
here to comment on this item?
Public comment going once, going twice,
public comment. Is there any public on
in Zoomland? I haven't asked that in the
past.
Okay, public comment is closed.
Um,
does the applicant want to come forward
and address a couple of the issues that
came up during the sta staff questions,
please?
>> Mr. Chair through John Sers again for
True Great Land Development. So,
we have no intentions of putting
business over in this area because the
need for housing in on the south side is
tremendous at this point with the amount
of phone calls we are fielding on a
regular basis with everything
increasing. Um, this pl piece of land
had always been designed to be apartment
complex along there. So, it acted as a
buffer in between as we already have
apartments pretty much along that
stretch. In regards to commercial, uh
staff did indicate, yeah, South Gley is
your closest real commercial less. Um
there is a uh
campground south of us over there, but
it's it's intermixed. And then there's
residential completely to the south of
us as well. So there has been no
intentions of putting any mixeduse
business over in that area with that
idea. We have already uh contracts
working towards getting the uh 524s that
we have in play up in over in that area.
Those individuals would also have to
join the HOA so as to help maintain the
park area. So everything by the
guidelines of what was the original PUB
per se is still all donating towards the
park and maintenance of all the open
space areas that we have in that area.
So no one is uh blighted by not taking
care of that andor from that situation.
I will say just like we did on uh
Richard Martin, we replatted that a
while back. Those individuals got hit
one more time for a separate HOA over at
top only because they have an alley
behind them. And so we went ahead and
they are part of the full HOA, but they
are the only ones that would maintain
the alley behind because it is only to
their benefit. So that is the only way
that we go about maintaining certain
areas even more so. So nobody would
maintain this particular area. It all go
it would be the HOA for these five
buildings. The HOA for the park and open
space further up is all taken care of by
everybody else at that point. If that
answers your questions.
>> So to clarify, you're saying this is an
HOA. It has an HOA that's going to take
care of their parking, but they are not
going to contribute to the park or they
are going to contribute to the park that
is part of the rest of the ED.
>> Mr. Chair, through you, they will
contribute to the park which is
privately owned and not
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> through the city.
>> Okay. And and just for the record, did I
hear you correctly state that by
going this route with this resoning, you
were able to gain an additional eight
units, eight housing units relative to
what was available under the PUD?
>> Mr. Chair, through you that that is the
case along with not having a manager's
office and so forth. That is not
necessary based on the ownership of the
building having its own ownership for
individual lease and rent.
>> Okay. Thank you. Or
any other questions for applicant to
clean? Well, I guess you address the
questions that were Did we miss any
questions that were reserved for the
applicant?
Hearing none,
I I guess I'm listening for either a
discussion to inform a motion or a
motion please from the commission.
>> Mr. Chair,
this Tony
>> Leard. Yes. I move to approve the
reszoning of lot one block one Harmony
Valley fourth f fil filing to NR3
neighborhood residential high density as
shown in the attached zone change map
noting that the project meets the review
criteria for approval.
>> Thank you. Do I have a second?
>> Second. Seconded by Commissioner Ma.
Um, any discussion on the motion on the
table from the commission?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. This is Tony.
>> Commissioner. Yeah, Commissioner Lair.
>> I I'm I'm kind of disappointed that
there's not going to be some kind of
commercial development here because I
I'm I'm just really concerned about this
whole big area. It seems like all the
commercial development is being
concentrated along South Wheelley
Highway and nothing dispersed further
away. And like we talked about before,
this is fairly highdensity housing. A
lot of people living near here, and
they're a pretty long way at this point
from South Kley Highway. There's
obviously some interstate type services
over at the I25 interchange, but uh I I
don't think I don't think this is the
appropriate time, I guess, with this
action to I I don't think there's any
way this commission can can force that
and this developer could build the
apartments with slightly less density
and those other requirements under the
PUD. And it sounds like that's what they
were originally planning to do anyway,
uh with no commercial. I'm I'm gonna
have I have kind of the same concern two
items from now when we're talking about
the intersection at Waltershide and
Allison, which also seems like an
opportunity with two major roads or some
kind of uh commercial retail type
development, but anyway, I I will
support the motion uh kind of
reluctantly.
Any further discussion or amendments to
the motion on the table
hearing? None. Will staff please call
the roll.
>> Tony Leard.
>> Hi.
>> Bob Mati.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Hi.
>> Lonnie Olsson. I,
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Thank you. And as a kind of a followup,
do we have an update of the community
plan that would address kind of future
land use and anticipated commercial
addressing kind of the broader area?
Before we read the next item into the
record,
>> chair members of the planning
commission, it's presently stuck behind
uh farm related ordinances and stuff
like that that's become our priority
recently, drafting agricultural rules
and regulations. So is slightly delayed.
>> Okay. Thank you. But it's something that
we may be able to address here sooner
rather than later. Okay. Thank you. Will
staff please read item D into the
record?
Item D, PUDC-26-27,
Harmony Valley zoning map amendment.
>> Will the applicant please come forward?
>> Mr. Chair, John Sers again representing
True Grit Land Development. Um,
[clears throat] so I kind of need to go
back through a little of the history
with this. What you're looking at is the
last piece of land uh that was in the
PUD. We did not choose to go ahead and
pull that out of the PUD previously
because we didn't need to when we were
doing what is known as Harmony Valley
Fifth Filing. Harmony Valley Fifth
Filing is the lots that are directly
north of York, as you can see, that have
roads and alleys off the rear. The
reason we chose to do that was the
product that we are looking at is
cottage lots that have alley load. It it
allowed for smaller, denser lots than
the actual PUB zoning we had in play at
the time. in working with staff roughly
a year ago, we were able to go ahead and
plat this piece of land, get it
recorded, and it is what you see today.
Um, tomorrow morning, we have a meeting
at uh BOPU for precon. So, we will start
construction on that next week um to
move forward with uh those lots that are
desperately needed. With that said, um
we went forward at this time so we can
put in the next plat, which would be
Harmony Valley 23rd filing. The 23rd
filing will take into account Carolan
Way moving all the way over to what is
Grand Harmony Boulevard as well as Danny
Place. Subsequently, all the alleys that
are in play will extend over to Danny
Place as well as putting in some
different lots only for our twin home
product that is attached and our single
family attached products that fit the
price point for what we are seeing
people able to buy and be a first-time
home buyer with that product.
The piece of land that shows the two big
pieces left over is part of the 23rd
filing. There is no intent at this time
whatsoever. It's not even designed in
the plat to bring forward any apartment
complexes in this area. Um, we are
working on 196 lots that vary from 41.5T
wide to 97 feet deep on a common uh lot
line that will go ahead and have that
attached for the units to be provided
for that area. I know this map doesn't
show it as well and I wish I could have
brought you the other, but we literally
were in meetings till this meeting
tonight trying to tighten up some of the
details on that. But there is green
space in between the areas. So you'll
have a situation where you have a road.
The front door must face the road. Then
the alley load is where the residents
would actually pull into the back side
of the unit. Then you can see on the
flip side that you'd have another the
alley would service both sides. And then
we actually built in green spaces so
there's corridors for everybody to walk
around in this area as to continuing
with what we did with the park area
being its own park for this area not a
city park all maintained by the
residents of the area. That plat it
moves forward into submitt next
Wednesday and that will be the 23rd
filing. So there will be 196 lots
strictly single family or attached
dwellings at that point with no
apartment complex, no trailer park, no
none of that stuff. U we just weren't
able to get it in fast enough to get
that done as we were modifying it and
working with the school district in
regards to the topography out in this
area. So to get back to our situation,
the vacant land just to the west of
there was zoned NR3 previous or PUD.
When we went ahead and did the plat to
keep everything uniform, we went ahead
and did that zone to an NR3 knowing we
were coming back in to continue those
same exact lots all the way across. The
intent is is to get Grand Harmony
Boulevard to go up parallel to the
previous uh residential area to the east
and and get them an access to Allison to
take some of the burden off the area and
give them to where they don't have to go
out to South Gley. The other part of
this that staff with city is working on
is York is going to tie into Cribbon. So
it gives them the second to surround the
junior high and high school up there at
the time. And I believe that's supposed
to let out at 2028. So we've been
working on this with with city staff for
quite some time. All we are simply doing
is doing exactly what we did before PUD
to an NR3 to make the residential lots
fit for the cottage dial lots because
they did not fit previously and that's
why we went ahead with the Harmony
Valley fifth filing. Subsequently, we
will be doing the same thing with the
Harmony Valley 23rd filing on the next
middle next Wednesday. happy to address
any questions.
>> Okay. Thank you. Um commissioners, any
questions for the applicant?
Any of the commissioners online?
I I guess I have have one. Um,
can you address in this
in in in this instance that how many
additional housing lots you're able to
accomplish
under the NR3 that that wouldn't have
been available within the PED or have
you done that calculation?
>> Mr. Chair, through you I have not. And I
will tell you the basis for that was is
that the idea was um the idea of a 6,000
square foot lot. Those aren't selling.
That's that's the biggest prime reason
of why we've had to come back in and and
narrow these lots down. So again, I
would reference uh our lot size is 41.5
ft wide by 97 feet deep for our attached
single family dwelling product that has
started to move rather well. We ran out
of lots. Uh the only other product that
we would be putting over there is our
twin home product that has sold
tremendously. Um we just put uh 20 of
those on LCG. We're not even finished
construction and they're all sold out.
So we're just trying to meet the market
demand for the square footage and the
price point that is allowable at that
point. And that's that is the two
products that we are flipping through
there at that point.
>> Okay. Just do we have any kind of a
projected notion of how many total lots
are going to wind up in in what was the
PUB the Harmony Valley?
>> Mr. Mr. Chair, you I can give you only
this number. So Harmony Valley fifth
filing and the 23rd right now will be
308 lots and the only reason I know that
is I was doing lot counts prior to this
meeting doing my spreadsheet. The next
phase is 196 and the fifth filing was
112.
Yeah,
>> not including the open space green
spaces that are in place as well, but
that is the number for residential
units, sir.
>> Okay, thank you.
Um
staff, you please present your report.
>> Morgan Dennis, Planning and Development.
Um, this is a zone change request for
lot 2 block 10. Harmony Valley first
filing from Harmony Valley PUB to NR3.
Surround zoning for this area is public
and AG to the north, Harmony Meadows PUB
to the east, mixeduse business to the
south, and public
and an existing NR3 zone to the west.
The AG zone to the north is undergoing a
zone change as well. The f
the future land use map designates this
area as urban residential and with a
small portion to the south being
designated as mixeduse residential. Both
designations promote highdensity
residential developments. This zone
would be an extension of the existing
NR3 zone. The current designation
of this parcel within the Harmony Valley
PUB is medium density, which is similar
to the NR3 zone. This parcel is in
between a school and an existing
neighborhood. And while there is no
activity center nearby, there is
existing pedestrian networks in the
area. With this application meeting
review criteria, staff recommends
approval for this zone change.
Okay, thank you. Morgan,
does commission have any questions for
staff?
Commissioners online
hearing none.
Is there I I guess I I should probably
ask the same question I asked about the
last one. Does staff have any concerns
about pulling this out of the PUD? Does
it somehow compromise the PUD to remove
it? I think I know the answer, but for
the record,
>> Mr. Chair, for the record, we do not.
Um, this section of the PUD is now
disconnected from the other rest of the
PUD. Um, so it's kind of already
anticipated to
um flex into something else, whether
that's NR3 zoning or some other
development pattern. Um just it it seems
that the Harmony Valley PUB is basically
just going to exist um south and west of
of York.
Okay.
Are there is there anybody from the
public that is here that has
comments regarding this this item?
Please come forward, sir.
and please read your and give us your
name and address for the record.
>> Howdy. My name is Richard Hammet. I live
at 1326 Concerto. I'm just on the
eastern border of this uh uh
property border. Um I just have a
question. There are some very large uh
power lines that run along that border
and I was just wondering is there and
pardon me for not necessarily knowing
the right terms. Is there like an
easement of where
properties will not be built or is it
going to butt right up against the fence
line for the existing
>> Okay. Thank you. And and when we get to
the point of of calling the applicant
forward, we can we can address that. Uh
for the record, this is on the zoning.
This is not the platting. And I I
believe your question is a plat
question, but but we can we can ask the
applicant. Um, any other members of the
public have any uh comments?
Yes, sir.
Get your name and address.
>> Don Thomas, one8 Contto Lane.
>> Yes.
>> Um, I'll just Did he say that he's going
to try to direct more traffic onto
Allison?
>> Well, will we will
>> when he spoke earlier?
>> I That's
>> He mentioned something about Allison. I
didn't get what he meant.
Okay. And and any other uh comments,
questions, concerns about that for the
record?
>> Well, I want to know if that's what he's
got in mind. Is he going to direct more
traffic onto Allison that the high
school kids think it's a racetrack?
>> Is it that's already a problem?
>> Well, there's more to it,
>> sir. If you've got other things that you
want to bring up, I suggest you bring
them up and before I close a public
comment.
Is that your long question?
Well, we'll get to the point where the
applicant will come forward and address
questions at the end. I don't want a
bunch of back and forth. So, if you've
got other things, would you please
present them assuming the answer is yes.
Okay. Any other questions from the
public? Comments from the public?
>> Sir,
please come forward.
>> Hi, my name is uh Zachary Gerkin. I live
at 109 Conserto.
>> Okay.
>> Um, so the property in discussion is
basically my front window view. Okay.
>> So, when I heard about the zoning
change, I was definitely concerned
about, you know, seeing and writing high
density. I thought they were going to
pack in as many apartments as they
could. So, when you hear, you know,
split up to 196 parcels, pretty small
lots, that's quite a bit more traffic
through there. um in in the housing um
development next to it, there is a dead
end that I would assume be connecting to
this property once it's developed. Uh my
concerns are more vehicle traffic
through there. um along with uh his
point of or saying alleviating
traffic going to college, you would
actually need to alleviate traffic not
going to Allison uh due to the school
and the traffic that goes through there
in the morning. I don't know if they've
done a traffic study, but go there
between 8 and 9 in the morning and
you'll see it's a bottleneck between all
these roads that connect in through here
going up Allison to the high school and
the junior high coming back down that
hill to where that property, you know
what the line of the projected zoning
change it
traffic goes all the way up to there.
how those people going to get in or out?
Not to mention that those roads aren't
really very wellmaintained. They're
usually pretty icy. I can't see um
unskilled drivers talking about the uh
high school students uh
stopping. I can see that being a
potential problem. Uh not to mention um
as far as uh the schools are concerned
everywhere in and around there and past
college on the south side is all
considered walking distance.
So um currently, you know, my kids walk
through that field to get to the junior
high or the high school. So that's
another concern. Um,
yeah, those that's all I have to comment
about.
>> Okay, thank you.
Anybody else from the public wish to
comment on this? Please come forward.
Sir, my name is Josh Brown. I live at
938 Conerto. Uh my property butts right
against the uh sorry my property butts
right against the uh uh the uh new
zoning area. Um my concerns were
actually alleviated mostly by the by uh
the distinction that they're not
planning on putting in a lot of big
apartment complexes. But I do have some
remaining concerns. Um speaking towards
the traffic um portion of it, it's not
just on Alison where this is going to
cause potential issues. I want to make
sure I say that correctly. Potential
issues. Um but uh there's a four-way
stop at um Walter Seed and and Leisure
um which already bottlenecks in the
morning and in the afternoon uh peak
times. Um stop light at school zone to
the south uh at college which also
bottlenecks at peak times. And then also
the stop light from Allison on to South
Gley which also bottlenecks a lot during
the day because of the businesses there.
Um all there's a concentration of
businesses at the end of that street
along with high school at the other end.
or uh if we have uh a large influx of um
of residential units, I see this causing
more traffic issues. I did note that
there had been a uh uh thorough traffic
um uh analysis done when it was
previously turned into a PUD from
agriculture. I'm just wondering if
there's going to be an updated um uh
traffic uh uh analysis as in so far as
how it'll be impacted. Secondly, um I
noted that even when it was turned into
a PD previously, there had been no
mention of a um uh uh capacity or a
school capacity analysis. Um we're
adding a lot of a lot of new residents
there. The high school is kind of small,
the junior high is kind of small, and we
have Gwins and Rossman there. They're
all they're both kind of small as well.
I'm wondering if anyone's done any uh
coordination with the school district to
make sure that the schools aren't going
to breach capacity and if they are going
to if there's going to be any plans to
make um uh changes to the schools
themselves to uh accommodate more
students. Um and then the last one that
I have is has there been an analysis in
so far as emergency uh services and
their ability to reach these new areas
and accommodate the new residents. So
these are the these are the uh concerns
that I have currently.
Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Any other members of the public wish to
comment on this item before we turn it
over to try to respond to questions and
comments.
Public comment going once. Public
comment going twice.
Public comment uh closed.
I think I'd like to ask staff to address
the questions if it's appropriate that
were
I I guess more focused on staff issues
uh feedback school district uh traffic
study updates anything like that
>> Mr. Mr. Chair, this is Seth Lloyd with
the planning and development department.
Um I would note that um our most recent
understanding from the school district
is that their long range plans show a
decrease in population of schools even
as Cheyenne may grow in population due
to decreased number of families of
school age children, decreased number of
children per family. Um the Mercer study
that came out last year closed eight
elementary schools um due to an
anticipated decrease in need for those
schools. Um as far as traffic impact
studies, um it's my understanding that
we typically request those with platting
actions um uh traffic analysis. Uh we do
have an engineer in the room that could
address more detailed questions on that
specific to this project if that is um
needed.
[clears throat]
I would note that the overhead power
lines that run through the area do have
easements over them. Um and I believe
our applicant may have to deal with
those easements as well. Um they will
not be able to build structures of any
type underneath those power lines. Um uh
so they'll be restricted in development
getting too close to the property next
door at least for the southern or
majority of that property line due to
those easements. Um I anticipate that
these are big enough and um important
enough power lines that are applicant
will not try to underground them or
relocate them. Um so I think those will
stay where right where they are. Um I
believe a street um stub was mentioned
from Harmony Meadows into Harmony
Valley. Um on analysis it looks like
that street stub was not graded to
connect as a street. Um so we anticipate
having that be a pedestrian connection
as opposed to a full vehicular
connection. So that way this
neighborhood, the Harmony Valley
neighborhood and the Harmony Meadows
neighborhoods could still walk to each
other's but they wouldn't have traffic
driving from one neighborhood through
the other. Um
it is also our understanding that our
fire department is aware of um needs for
fire department services and is actively
looking at new locations for fire
stations um around the community as a
whole. They've been doing some
significant analyses. They already have
closed two fire stations and built two
new ones. Um I maybe it's three I think
it's three new ones actually. Um so they
are the fire department's very much
aware of future growth patterns um and
future services that are needed. Um and
so as this area develops the fire
department's very much aware of
providing emergency services. Um I think
that covers most of the questions. I
would note that a long a short-term goal
of the city is to connect York to
Kribbon. Um, as York goes up and through
Harmony um, Valley, it will connect into
Cribbon, which is just west of South
High School, which will likely change
traffic patterns significantly in the
area. Um, we don't know exactly how
that's going to change things, but that
is on the radar of the city. Don't know
exactly where it is in the status. I
just asked our engineer previous to this
and I I don't know if we have an update
as to exactly when that will happen, but
it's my understanding that is in
process. Um
I I I don't generally speaking with
traffic and roads, roadways, um
development all along along a roadway
typically slows traffic down. Um, right
now Allison has some stretches that are
pretty wide open and that makes people
feel like they can go faster. Um,
increase it. I'm not saying that it will
happen here. I'm just saying that that's
general the general rule is the more um
buildings, trees, other items that are
in the viewshed of a driver, usually the
driver will go slower. Um, I can't
guarantee that will happen here, but I
also can't guarantee that traffic will
go faster or slower um with more traffic
this location. I that was expressed as a
concern as far as speed on Allison goes.
Um, so the development may help that,
but I I wouldn't guarantee that. I just
would note that that's traditionally
what happens with development and
traffic. I think that answers all the
questions that I heard. um our applicant
may have other answers to questions that
it may be more appropriate for the
applicant to answer.
>> And maybe as a followup before we get to
you uh to get to the applicant. Um I
also heard concern about queuing traffic
congestion which would be a volume
thing. Uh secondly, is it do I
understand that if there's a platting
action brought forward next Wednesday? I
think I heard next Wednesday that would
be when the traffic study update
would would be part of that. Correct.
>> Mr. Chair, the applicant has stated they
are planning to submit a plat um for the
land that is at least part of the land
that is associated with this request. Um
that would come through the planning
commission. um uh if they submit by
before next Wednesday, they would be
going to the May Planning Commission. Um
so anyone who's interested in this
project might want to circle the May
Planning Commission date on their
calendars. Um uh due to the way our code
is written, there is no mailed notice
for planning action. Um and I
unfortunately I don't think very many
people read the newspaper and get the
legal notice. Um, so we'll go ahead and
say that right here is we anticipate
that would be a May planning commission
item. Um, based on when the applicant
has said they would submit. Um, and so
that would give more details as to
exactly how that land would develop, how
the streets would connect. Presumably, a
traffic documentation would be submitted
with that planning action as well, but
I'll let the applicant and possibly our
engineer speak to that.
And for the record, I'm trying to look
real quickly that that would be the May
4th planning commission.
>> Am I correct,
>> Mr. Chair? That'd be correct. First
Monday in May.
>> First Monday in May, 6 o'clock
presumably here. Okay. Would the
applicant like to address any of the
remaining outstanding questions?
Some of which are traffic related. I
believe
>> Mr. Chair through John S's addressing.
So the first comment that was made was
the power line easements. WA does have a
35 foot easement both sides of the power
poles that they just put in. So you
cannot build within that area. If you
did build within that area, which
nobody's, we just built the apartment
complexes down to the south. We had to
have WA verify that we were outside of
it. Um unfortunately though, I can say
that some of the houses that were
constructed over in Harmony Meadows are
in violation of the 35 foot easement.
But that's not mine, Gus. I we met with
the WAPA uh engineers on site in regards
to traffic. So this is a touchy subject,
but it's an interesting subject. So we
want interconnectivity. We want to get
people to move around. So we were asked
a long time ago when we were doing the
original fifth filing and the redesign
of this to see if we can get Grand
Harmony to go to Allison. So, we
complied and now we're catching grief
that we're going to put access on to
Allison, which is exactly what would
make sense because it's not going
through Harmony Meadows because the
whole entire Harmony Meadows has only
two spots for them to get in and out of.
That's it. So, with Harmony Valley 23rd
filing, you actually have multiple ways
to get out in different areas. As I was
talking with staff engineering and met
with Tom Cobb last week, um Tom has
voiced me and because we're working onus
and understandings on a couple other
things, the funding for York to go up to
Cribbon and complete that won't be
available till 2028. But the engineer
who already has designed and has that in
play
has it I think at 98 90% complete at
this time period. So, that's already in
the design process, but it's the
economics to get it constructed at this
point, and that's a separate project
outside of our area. Um,
as to Allison, it is considered a major
roadway in the area to feed all of
those. So, that is where the traffic
needs to go. Um, I can understand um the
concern for traffic more particularly on
the four-way stop that you represented
earlier. Um, I wish some people in this
town knew how to work a four-way stop at
up by the fire station at the top of the
hill there because uh how more accidents
don't occur in that situation and the
stacking in the morning is ridiculous.
And I I'll be the first one. I I
literally travel that every day at the
times that you pointed out. I can't
understand how two cars can't go
straight, two cars can't go straight or
simultaneously turn. Uh they they don't
understand the rules. So that adds to
the backup and staging. So, I know I'm
getting a smile, but yes, I' I've been a
part of that in the mornings and it's
frustrating to me. Um, so that that is
the traffic situation. In regards to
Melody Lane, I think it is or Melody
Loop. I I'm not going to the connection
that went to the west there. There's no
way to get that to tie into Grand
Harmony. Um, flat out because of
topography. Um, we've looked at multiple
ways to make it happen and it's not. Um,
we deal with the trespassing on a daily
basis. Um, we put a fence up. U, we have
stopped the kids walking through that
area and asked them to go up and through
uh, a different area. We have begg,
plead and cried with the, um, school
district on the access of them cutting
through the property because actually
it's a liability for us if they get hurt
out there. Um, there is no pedestrian
pathway. It's just a vacant piece of
land that's ours and it's trespassing.
So, we kindly ask all the time, uh,
please don't travel through here, but it
it happens. So, um, with these pathways
that we're looking at putting in and
trying to get access up to Allison,
we're trying to eliminate a lot of that
congestion as everyone has asked. I
mean, on one hand, we asked us to do
certain things and then others get
upset. Um, traffic study was previously
done. I know that we are looking into
modifying whether how that looks. That's
in the works at this point. In regards
to schools, so we're bound by Laramie
County School District. So, I've been
dealing with uh Triumph High School, uh
South High School, um and I believe,
don't quote me, but Rossman over at
Wallakin Division. Uh they're trying to
build the 56 over there right now. So,
we actually have ties to that as well.
Been working with uh the school district
and their construction department on
that with all the different levels. Um
the 56 is supposed to get started within
the next year and so that's going to
eliminate some of that as uh Seth Lloyd
with planning pointed out. Yeah, they've
shut down schools and they're trying to
figure out which ones are keeping open
and not. I know most don't want to hear
this. They probably should have put the
56 up by the junior high and by the high
school for economic reasons, but they
don't want to do that. So that that ensu
lies the issue. Uh if I may continue on,
um the emergency service situation is in
play in the fact that uh in dealing with
the uh city staff and the mayor, they
are looking and have found potentially
other land as all these annexations keep
tying in as to where the next fire
station is. The closest one is up there
at the top of the hill by the tower. Um
and so I know that that would be the
first responding and closest units into
this. I know there is mutual aid with
district one on the south side as well.
They have the station on South Gley. So
there is the emergency services as
though it is being put into it's already
into the city. They are trying to figure
out where they're putting another
station, but it's going to depend on how
much further south the annexations
continue. I I I've been a part of the
trying to figure that out as well.
I believe that takes care of almost
everything that was brought up and
asked. If I missed something, please
courteously ask. I I I I wrote my notes
as we went through.
>> Okay. Thank you. And I think we can
confirm that that the plan is for Grand
Harmony to travel north and connect into
Allison.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay. That was a direct question that
was asked. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you. And would it be appropriate
to ask uh city engineering
to come forward, traffic engineering?
I've got a couple of questions I think
that float out of the I think I know
which questions we probably need to ask
based on
public comment.
>> Aaron Gates, city staff engineer.
>> Okay, thank you. Um, we heard some
questions about traffic, traffic
concerns, traffic studies. Um, we've got
a zoning in front of us that's
presumably going to increase the the
available
uh residential lots to some degree. Does
city does do you have any concerns about
the what it's going to do to the traffic
planning based on the additional uh
residential lots that would be created
with this zone change if it were to be
adopted.
>> We do not have any concerns with the
zone change and that is something uh
traffic study or traffic impact analysis
would be required with platting action.
>> Okay. And then that's what's coming up
next and that's when
>> correct
>> you can confirm that.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> All right.
>> And we've covered questions
from the
Can I reopen public comment for a
follow-up question
or no?
Okay. Well, I don't I don't want to be
out of order.
Yeah. And that's what I'm trying to
avoid. Okay.
I closed public comment. That's what we
were just discussing is procedurally
that Yeah. Well, it was before I I I
brought up staff to try to address the
questions. Okay. And with that uh
mission, do we do we have any discussion
or
I'm looking for a motion.
I move to approve the resoning of lot 2,
block 10, Harmony Valley, first filing
to NR3 neighborhood residential, the
high density, as shown in the attached
zone change map, noting that the project
meets the re review criteria for
approval.
>> Okay, I've got a motion
>> and I'll be looking for a second. And
and and and before we get too far into
this, just because I've got a restless
uh uh crowd here, I think most of the
traffic questions that were posed and
raised and and and the design,
that will all be part of of the platting
action that is not before us tonight,
but is scheduled for May. The only thing
that is before the commission is is the
zoning moving from what is essentially
the PUD that was high density to high
density to to this NR3
and and all that's going to do is is
change the number of lots that are
available.
So, and I heard a second from
Commissioner Leair, correct?
>> Yes.
Okay. And so we've got a motion on the
table. Do we have any discussion or
proposed amendments?
Discussion from the commission.
Hearing done. Hearing none.
Will staff please call call roll.
Lonnie Olsen.
>> Hi.
Megan Connor
>> I
>> Bob Matia
>> Tony Lert
>> I
>> Mr. chair. That motion passes and I
would just like to state for the record
just
>> for those here in the room as well, this
does go to city council next. So this is
not the final meeting it would be at. So
it's introduced at council next Monday
and then goes through three readings at
council.
>> Okay. Will staff please read item E into
the record.
PUDC-26-33
Allison property zoning map amendment.
>> Okay. And please come please feel free
to come back back in May when we get to
talk about what you want to talk about.
Okay. Thank you.
>> Will the applicant please come forward?
Mr. Chair John Sers, Representative for
True Great Land Development on number
three for us tonight. Um, previously we
tried to uh we were contacted that u
this piece of land uh originally was AR.
We moved to AG. Uh it was in county
zoning. We moved it back to city zoning
and proper designation. At that time uh
we did bring forward a site plan for
potential uh work camp. I need to make
sure the record is clear. We are not
building a work camp or building
anything at this time period. Um the
only thing is is that we have had uh
multiple parties contact us in regards
to uh possible uses for this land and
the best fit that we have seen at this
time period is NR3. Um I understand
through this conversation tonight that
many people would like more business
over there. Well, the problem is if we
bring more business into the area now
you have more traffic. then you have
even more problems than the ones that we
already have incurred and/or screaming
and yelling or frustration and pounding
hands. Um at this time we do not have a
clear definition of what we are planning
on moving forward with this. We have had
multiple parties reach out to us with
possible ideas. I have not been privy to
those at this time period, but it was
recommended that at this time period we
simply go forward with NR3. it's the
next step step towards potential of
somebody coming on board and whether or
not they submit a site plan based on
residential or how that may fit. I can't
answer that because we do not know at
this time. Um but with it being no
zoning at that time at this time period
leaving it in agricultural it leaves it
to them doing another step and we're
just trying to go ahead and move forward
at this time to get it to match across
the street and move forward and happy to
take any questions.
Okay, thank you. Are there any questions
from uh from uh the commission for the
applicant
questions?
Hearing none of staff, please present
your report.
>> Morgan Dennis, Planning and Development.
This is a zone change for a parcel
located northwest of the intersection of
West Allison Road and Waltershide
Boulevard from AG to NR3.
Surrounding the surrounding zone for
this parcel is county A1 to the north,
Harmony Valley
and Meadows PUD to the south, county
urban residential low density that is
currently being annexed into the city
and would be designated MR to the east
and public and MR to the west.
Harmony Valley PUD parcel.
The Harmony Valley PUD parcel to the
south is undergoing a zone change to
NR3. If that was to be approved, NR3
would not be isolated zone in this area.
Future land use
future land use map designates this
property as mixeduse commercial. This
designation supports more commercial or
live work developments that could be
activity centers. Uh residential
developments are typically secondary in
this designation and should be high
density developments. This lot is
located at the intersection of Allison
Road and Waltershed Boulevard to hightra
streets. This results in higher volumes
of traffic than might be desired in
residential areas. The optimal zone for
this area would be the MUB mixeduse
business zone. Although a mix of
commercial and highdensity residential
zones may also accomplish the
comprehensive plan objectives. Based on
the policies and future land use map,
NR3 is not the most appropriate for this
area. The intersection is lacking in
commercial zoning and through commercial
zoning even though commercial zoning
exists less than 200 ft to the northeast
of the subject property. This parcel is
not located near any activity center,
but has commercial de development to the
east and schools nearby. Pedestrian
amenities, including the greenway, are
in the area. The comprehensive plan does
support flexibility to adjust
to market demands and supports the
development of housing to meet these
demands.
Uh while the NR3 will limit overall
allowable de development action within
the area, adding housing units will meet
market and development demands. With
this application meeting review
criteria, staff recommends approval for
this zone change.
I stand for questions.
>> Does the commission have any questions
for staff?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. This is Tony.
>> Go ahead.
Uh just I just wanted to verify both
Allison Road here and Waltershide are
arterial roadways.
>> M
we've got our traffic engineer coming.
>> We'll defer to the traffic engineer.
Aaron Gates, staff engineer. Uh Allison
is a major collector.
>> Okay. And and Walter Shide is a is an
arterial.
>> Minor arterial.
>> Minor art. Yeah. Thank you.
>> Does that answer your question,
Commissioner Leair, or do you have
follow-up questions?
>> No, it does answer my question, but I'm
I'm I'm a little concerned about the uh
robustness of the traffic network in
this uh high growth area of the city.
Uh staff, do you have a particular
question we can pose to staff about
that?
No, not in not in particular. I just
wanted to know what the plan was now.
This probably not not necessarily
other than comment, not necessarily our
role to wonder about the traffic
network, but it just it seems kind of
odd with a lot of density.
All right, staff care to respond.
>> And chair, members of the commission,
Charles Bloom, planning and development
director. Um, York is actually shown as
a minor collector um as it heads out
through the Harmony Valley Development
[clears throat] and so is the northern
uh
uh portion of or the southern portion of
Cribbon as approaches Allison. And
there's also another minor collector
that essentially
uh comes up Grand Harmony Boulevard and
it maners its way to the north to
provide some additional connectivity
through that neighborhood up to Allison.
So there are two minor collectors that
are designed to intercept and disperse
traffic in that area.
>> Thank you. Any further questions or
comments, commissioners
or staff?
Hearing none, I'll no now open this
hearing up for public comment. Are there
any members of the public that want to
offer comment
or ask questions?
Public comment going once, going twice.
Public comment is closed.
I'm now looking for a motion or I guess
discussion that would lead to a motion
from the commission.
>> I move to approve the reszoning of 14.47
47 acres of land northwest of and
adjacent to the intersection of
Watershield Boulevard and Allison Road
to NR3 neighborhood residential high
density as shown in the attached zone
change map noting that the project meets
the review criteria for approval.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved and seconded.
Any discussion by the commission
or proposed amendments? Discussion
hearing none. Will staff please call
roll.
>> Bob Mati
>> I.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Hi.
>> Lonni Olsson.
>> Megan Connor.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair. That motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Will staff please read item F into the
record.
Item F, uh, PUDC-26-34,
sweetg grass PUB amendment.
Okay, thank you. I note in
in the packet that
this I believe this is
postponed or it is slated for
postponement.
Mr. Chair, uh Conor Way Planning and
Development Department. Yes. Um
I don't know if we want to let the if
the applicant wants to speak, they can.
Um but yes, the recommendation is for
postponement of this item to the April
6th uh planning commission meeting.
>> Do we have an applicant present who
might want to
>> Mr. Chair through you? Yes. Um Mr. Palma
is online.
>> Okay. Well, with that,
>> chair, can you all hear me?
>> Yes, Mr. Palma.
>> This is Casey Palma, Palma land planning
agent for the owner. Um we uh we did
request postponement of this. We had not
mailed the notice to all the land
owners. There's about 350 in and around
Sweetgrass that need notified. Um and we
also are just kind of making sure with
staff that we have all the nuances of
this amendment um kind of buttoned up
before we came to you. So, uh, we hope
to have everything sorted out and come
back to you next month and, um, have
this all ready to go.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Does commission want to ask any
questions of a of an applicant that's
seeking postponement?
Hearing none,
uh, staff here to provide a report.
>> Mr. chair uh members of commission
counterweight planning development
department as the applicant m mentioned
um they didn't meet the requirement for
ma notice and then staff is working
through just review and comments um so
this does give us a little bit more time
to do that to make sure everything is
kind of all in order before we bring it
back to you um in April so staff does
recommend the postponement um of this
item
>> and for the record uh that would the
April 6th,
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Yes. April 6th,
planning commission.
>> Okay. Thank you. Do I need to open this
up to public com? Okay. With that, um
I'm looking for I guess either questions
from from the commission or a motion.
>> Mr. Chair,
>> Commissioner Leair,
>> I've lost the screen here.
I
>> Commissioner Leard, you just lost the
floor. Also, did I hear Commissioner
Olsen?
>> Uh, Chair, I if Commissioner Lar wants
to make the motion, he can. I think we
were both shooting for the same thing.
>> Well, you've got the floor now,
Commissioner.
>> Well, Chair, I move to postpone this
item to the April 6, 2026 planning
commission meeting.
>> Okay. Thank you. Do I have a second?
>> Second.
Okay. Comm seconded by Commissioner
Mthay.
Will staff please call roll or I guess
is there any discussion
>> hearing? None. Will staff please call
roll.
>> Lonnie Olsen.
>> Hi.
>> Megan Connor.
>> I.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Hi.
>> Bathia.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair. That motion passes. Thank
you. And did I need a roll call on that?
That works.
>> Okay.
Uh, will staff
>> voting? Yes.
>> Will staff please read item G into the
record?
>> Item G, PUDC-26-36,
Frank Court vacation.
>> Okay. Thank you. Do we have an applicant
here to present this? Mr. Chair, staff
is the applicant.
>> Okay.
Well, will staff please present their
report.
Uh, Mr. Chair, members of the
commission, counterway planning and
development department. So, the
application before you is a street
vacation. Um, the UDC does allow staff
to petition
uh, city council basically to vacate
streets. We do go through planning
commission first. Um, but basically this
is a staff petition to do the vacation.
Um,
a little context, this is east of North
College Drive and north of Rock Spring
Street.
Um,
zoning and future land use doesn't
really matter for a street, but we do
have it on here just showing kind of
adjacent zones. Um, this will give you a
better idea of the location though and
what we're talking about. You may
remember that I want to say it was
January maybe we had the preliminary
plat for Dry Creek Vistas. Um, one of
the conditions on there was that the
applicant provide staff with a vacation
map to basically vacate all of Frank
Court. Um, as they would like to plat
that into the adjacent properties to the
east. um but they were not able to get
signatures from all property owners that
have basically a vested interest in the
vacation. So with that basically staff
is able to petition and vacate streets
without uh signatures.
With this vacation, it is getting rid of
a street that is basically used as a
driveway for two homes. Um, the property
that is at the southwest
corner, uh, I did find out they do use
this as basically access to their rear
garage, but with the vacation, the land
that they're probably using to get in
there does become theirs. So, they are
getting half that street basically as
their own property. Um, as well as there
is an ease, access easement on the east
side that is being provided. And then
the property that is at the northeast
uh that's at the end of the street
that's basically their large driveway
getting into their house. So it is in it
is an undeveloped street. It is unpaved
um but it is city rightaway um that the
city is required to maintain and we're
basically maintaining it for two people.
Uh there is no
proposed connection for this road in the
future to go north. We do have dry creek
right there. So staff does believe that
the vacation of this street um it
wouldn't harm anything to do that. uh
half the street basically once you get
north of that southwest property uh the
northern kind of half will go to the
apartment complex that's to the west and
then the land to the east gets split
between the parcels that are adjacent to
it on the east side. There will be a
future platting action uh for the final
plat that will come back before you. Um
that is actually slated for next month.
That would be for the parcels to the
east uh that we had that preliminary
platform for.
This vacation also does vacate and kind
of clean up a southern alley that's at
that north west or southwest corner. Uh
the north part of that alley I believe
was vacated with a different action, but
they didn't get the southern half. So
this is cleaning that up as well.
Um
but through the review, city staff
didn't have any concerns with the
vacation of the street. It does have the
proper easements.
Um I believe we do have a couple of
conditions on this that are basically
conditions for ourselves. Uh just to get
the map cleaned up a little bit. Uh so
we are working with the applicant for
Dry Creek Vistas to get that map cleaned
up and those conditions um fulfilled.
One of those is there is a BOPU main
that stubs into the southwest portion of
Frank Court. So BOPU would like an
easement over that main or they'd like
it basically removed and capped. Um
being we're doing the vacation, we're
just going to request the easement at
this time. Uh, so BOPU has access still
to that main if they need to.
And then the other I think there might
have been one more condition that was
like a technical correction, but that's
really what we have uh for conditions.
With that, staff does recommend approval
of the vacation uh with conditions as
listed in the staff report.
I am available for any questions.
Does Commission have any questions for
staff?
>> Commissioner Ma.
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, through you. It seemed
like one of those two houses up there,
they didn't really want it to be
vacated. What happened there? [snorts]
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Um, we haven't
had any comments from the neighbors
about not wanting it vacated. I did have
a question from that Southwest property
owner that did contact me. That's I kind
of figured out they use it for their
garage. Um he contacted me after he got
the letter just wanting to know is he
still going to be able to access his
garage. So I did let him know that yes,
he will. Um he will have basically
you've got the access easement to the uh
east side of the vacation, but then also
he's going to own the land on the west
side. So he will have access uh to his
garage. Otherwise, he I haven't heard
anything from either property owner to
the west stating that they don't want it
to be vacated. I think the apartment
complex, they didn't really care.
They're not going to use it. Um, so they
didn't really have a stake in whether or
not it got vacated or not. Um, so I
haven't I haven't had anybody who has
said they didn't because the property
owners to the east, it's one property
owner and they would like it vacated. Uh
the two to the west, neither one has
specified that they don't want it
vacated. It was more just the one
question of can I still access my
property.
Okay. And thank you. I think you
addressed what was going to be my
question is is if there has been any
actual conversation with the
occupant of the house to the north on
the east side of it.
Okay. Any other questions for comment?
Any other questions for staff?
>> Mr. Chair, I guess just to for your
question again, the property owner
that's to the norththeast,
that house at the very end is the same
property owner as the larger parcel to
the southeast.
>> So, we may hear
>> they're wanting it to be vacated.
>> Yes.
Um, any other questions for staff from
the commission?
>> Mr. Chair, through you.
>> Commissioner Lar,
>> I probably need to ask Connor to explain
again the the easement that's going to
help serve that garage to that property
uh on the very south end to the west.
So, they're acquiring
half of the original road rightway, the
30 ft, but then in addition to that,
they're going to get an easement on most
of the rest of the eastern side. Is that
is that necessary to have that access
easement if they've got 20 or a new 30
ft of property that they're going to
own?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. So the reason
for that easement on the east side is
actually to provide access to the lot to
the very northeast
uh the house that's at the end of the
street. So basically that easement is
really for them but it is a full access
easement. So it technically would
provide access for the southwest
property as well. Um do they necessarily
need it? No, because they are owning 30
ft of the road that's already there. So
they can use that 30 ft. But I just kind
of made it as a statement that there
will also be an access easement on the
other side. But that access easement is
generally for the property that's at the
end of the street on the norththeast
side.
Did that answer your uh question,
Commissioner Lar?
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> And that raised another question for me.
Is there any other attorney that has
looked at this and the notion of having
an access easement serving a parcel that
is owned by the same owner is the person
with the access. I guess what I'm
concerned about and this is my day job
even though it's not my expertise.
Doesn't Aren't we setting this up for
having to figure out an easement later?
Because
the ownership of of both the dominant
and servant estate extinguishes the
easement. Has this if if we're counting
on there being an easement to replace
the right of way
and the two houses, the two parcels or
the parcels on the east side are all
under a single ownership. Does that not
mean the easement we're talking about is
going to go away as soon as it is
recorded?
>> Mr. Chair, this is Seth of the Planning
and Development Department. The common
law doctrine of merger and in regards to
easements and access easements and the
like um generally does not apply to
platted subdivisions. Um this property
will be going through a plat and the so
the easement will be on the face of the
plat. Um, that's case law from states as
varied as Idaho and West Virginia.
Sorry, Virginia, not West Virginia. Um,
also Pennsylvania has been doing that
since the 1910s apparently. Um, so the I
don't know if it's been challenged in
the state of Wyoming um, specifically,
but the general rule is that if you're
doing a subdivision and an easement is
shown on the subdivision of land, the
doctrine of merger does not apply and
you'd have to vacate or extinguish the
easement via a platting action or
whatever action the county or city or
um, governing body um, determines is
necessary to remove um, plat elements.
Okay, thank you. I'll trust you on that
one.
It's just a concern.
Any other questions?
I'll open this up to the public. Is
there anybody from the public that
wishes to comment on this?
Going once. Going twice. Public comment
is closed.
Do we have a motion from the commission?
Comment that would discussion that might
help formulate a motion?
Chair is looking for a motion.
I move to approve the vacation of Frank
Court north of Rock Springs Street and
Alley West of Frank Court as shown on
the attached vacation map, noting that
the project meets the review criteria
for approval with conditions.
>> Got a motion. And do I have a second?
>> Second.
>> Thank you. It's been moved and seconded
by uh Commissioner Leair. Correct.
>> Okay.
>> Do we have any discussion by the
commission?
>> Any comments, proposed amendments?
Hearing? None. Staff please call RO.
Tony Lair.
>> Hi
>> Megan Connor.
>> I
>> Lonnie Olsen
>> I.
>> Bob Matio
>> Mr. Chair, the motion passes.
Okay. Thank you.
And will staff please read item H into
the record.
>> Item H is PLTA-26-1
special use approvals creation of the
regional entertainment overlay and
development standards for offtrack
bedding facilities text amendment.
>> Thank you. And I believe this is also
the city. Will staff please you can read
a report or it looks like explain the
postponement.
>> Chair members of commission Charles Bo
planning and development director. Uh
this is a proposed unified development
code text amendment that really tackles
six different sections of our unified
development code. And [clears throat] I
was optimistic when I placed it on the
agenda because we have um wanted to get
this on the agenda and then um other
tasks moved ahead which uh sort of set
this aside from being completed. Um
right now what it is targeting is
revisions to our special use permit
process. Uh right now uh that is really
set up for oil and gas exploration and
it was primarily developed before the
unified development code. So it just
doesn't fold in very well. It refers to
the governing body as the governing body
which is appropriate. However, the rest
of the UDC refers to the governing body
as city council. So, some things are
just aligning that. Other things are
making it less go oil and gas
exploration
only. So, it would be uh able to be used
for other types of items that maybe
should be considered at the level beyond
the volunteer appointed basis. Um, one
of those such items is historic horse
racing, um, which is looking at, uh,
trying to find avenues where we can have
more local control at the elected level
instead of local control here at the,
uh, volunteer level. Um, is as part of
this, uh, staff envisions those
amendments to, uh, really, uh, get that
special use approval process up to snuff
and a little bit, um, able to be more
broadly applied. And but also it's
looking at creating an entertainment
overlay district that would be in select
areas of the community that would
essentially welcome and usher those in
where they might be uh best for regional
connectivity for revenue and and those
types of items. We can anticipate those
would be in areas where we would like to
see entertainment uses occur. Possibly
the Reed Rail corridor um interstate
interchanges um those types of items. In
addition, uh looking to establish, uh
development standards for offtrack
bedding facilities, um and an approval
process for areas that might not be in
those overweight districts. Um we are
fairly early in the process and um we do
anticipate that we will have a a good uh
draft that is ready for presentation uh
starting in April. Um, and that will at
least garner some discussion where we
will at least uh start moving down that
pathway. So, I don't have any questions
here except I'm just going to note that
we're requesting postponement. It's not
possible to improve approve anything
today because there's nothing presented.
Um, so we'll just continue to preserve
the uh notice that was given. And I
should note as this does come forward,
we are not intending to leave all of the
historic horse racing facilities that we
have in the community in the dark. They
all have a plethora of lights. So, we'll
can we'll be sure to um let them know of
these proceedings as we move forward.
Okay. Thank you. Any questions for staff
before I ask for a motion?
Hearing none.
Chair is looking for a motion on the
recommendation to postpone.
>> I move to postpone this item to the
April 6, 2026 planning commission
meeting.
>> Okay, I've got a motion. Do I have a
second?
>> I'll second.
>> It's been seconded by Commissioner Olsen
or moved by Commissioner Lar, seconded
by Commissioner Olsen.
Uh, any discussion of the motion on the
table?
Hearing none, will staff please call.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Hi.
>> Bob Mati.
>> I Olen.
>> Hi.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Thank you.
to other business and staff
announcements.
>> Chair, members of the commission,
Charles Bloom playing in the development
director. Um I don't have any real large
announcements that we have regarding um
activities in the in the department. Um
we do not have a midmon planning
commission meeting scheduled for this
midmon. So enjoy that day off. Um if
you'd like, we will be having our active
transportation advisory committee
meeting um that day and that'll probably
be located up in room 208. Um they are
uh presently working on revising our
bicycle lane and multiuse trails map.
This is the same map that we hand out
different events which shows where
people can um use active transportation
in our community to get from point A to
point B and occasionally point C. So
they're they're working on completing
that. Um ATAC is very interested in
making sure they can get this
information out to members of the
public. One of the next steps envisioned
is them to do an audit on what the map
shows right now to identify barriers
that may have been introduced or areas
where they're just not quite working or
working the way they were initially
designed back in 2012.
So, uh, stay tuned. We'll continue to
keep you all in the loop on that.
The last item I have is that we hope to
have our comprehensive plans RFP um out
for uh consultants to peruse um at the
beginning of next week or early next
week. Um that process is envisioned to
be an 18month
process to put this together and is
really that plan that's going to look at
land use. Um we have put together a lot
of uh parameters that are based on uh
pressing issues that we keep seeing rise
around us like for example data center
inquiries, data center development. How
does that reflect with uh lands that are
easier to develop for residential use?
What do we want to see uh for uh
development of lowhanging fruit lands?
And by low hanging fruit, I mean lands
that are close to existing
infrastructure, cheaper to develop. So
these are all some policies we're
looking at having um uh looked at in
this planning document as well as uh
some of our general ideas um and
requirements as street sections, street
standards, uh some development
requirements and processes.
And will this be the document that we
get to try to address the removal of
such a large portion of our projected
residential land for was it Cosmo? Was
that the one when we pulled out several
square miles worth of projected
residential for non-residential use? And
we've not really figured out where
that's going to go.
>> Chair three to the commission. Yes,
that's correct. This is the one that
will result in essentially a
recommendation for a land use plan. Uh
the intent right now, although it's
early, we're welcome to consulting
guidance is for this plan to uh develop
our recommended or the path forward
where we want to go with our land use
plan. And then we'll have our
independent document that we will adopt
um as the planning commission and
governing body and also include the
county concurrence as necessary.
But yes, it will.
>> Okay. And does active transportation map
include horseback.
>> Fair through you. Unfortunately, it does
not include um horseback. And I wonder
if horse if equestrian
usage is actually active transportation.
I guess you have to kick,
pull the reinss.
Oh, yes. But it does not. Short answer
does not.
Mr. Chair, Conway Planning and
Development Department. Um, just as a
note, you all should have received a new
copy of the UDC. Uh, make sure you use
the second version that I had sent out,
not the first. Uh, the first had some
text in there that has not come before
you yet.
um in blue and red an entire section.
Our engineering staff member isn't here,
I don't think anymore, but it is their
section of code. Um
but I have it basically already prepped
and in the UDC for when that does come
forward. It makes my life easier when we
get to the point of adoption. Um I
forgot to pull it out though when I
saved the final copy. Uh so you all
should have a new version. Um, and then
next month, expect another large agenda.
I think we're at eight items for next
month at this time. Could add more if we
get more zone changes in the next week.
Um, but right now we are sitting at
about I think eight items for that
agenda with these postponements.
So, please be prepared for another large
agenda. Please try to attend. So, we
have a quorum. Again, these are mostly
applicant items, not staff items.
So, applicants would like their projects
to move forward on a timely manner. Um,
other than that, I have no further
announcements.
Okay. With that, do I have a motion for
adjournment?
>> Mr. Chair, through you,
>> Commissioner Leair. In lie of that, I
wondered if uh I could ask if director
Bloom had any legislative updates he
wanted to share with us.
>> Well, thank you, Chair, members of the
commission, and Commissioner Lair. That
is a great reminder.
>> Yes, I do have legislative updates. Uh
this morning, shortly after 8:00 a.m.,
uh Dr. Mark Rainey, who's a council
member, was testifying in front of the
Senate Corporations Committee regarding
what I believe is House Bill 76. That
was the one um
regarding an annexation. And essentially
it said if a uh area an enclave is
surrounded by the annexing municipality
by 75% or more that it would allow for
anyone within that area to protest. And
a 50% of the uh residents and property
owners within that area uh by quantity
of land and by population if they
protest it would have immediately ceased
any and all annexation activity for 2
years. Essentially it would stop an
annexation process. Um if there was a
majority protest with 75% or more
surrounded by a jurisdiction. um that
bill did not uh pass, did not get out of
the Senate today. Um another item that
did fail, this was on Friday,
I don't have the number exactly in front
of me, but it was a Senate file which um
was in regards to changes to the protest
vote provisions of state statute. Uh
Holland Court and the reasonzoning up
there is still pretty fresh in
everyone's memory. uh where a
neighborhood filed protest and it
triggered a supermajority
vote or threearters vote of the
governing body for it to be approved.
When we have 10 members of a governing
body, it would have required eight
affirmative votes for it to approve.
This proposed amendment, it uh changed
the ability to protest for the area uh
to a little bit larger, but it still had
an adjacency clause. So, you had to be
adjacent and up to 300 ft. So, it sort
of gave a little bit more weight for uh
property owners that had larger tracks
of land. Generally, those folks don't
protest. It's the smaller ones that
protest. It also uh changed the
threshold to just a uh supermajority
vote, so 2/3,
which would have uh changed the way our
governing body does business by only
requiring seven affirmative votes to
pass something with protest. Uh this was
a a piece of legislation that we
ultimately wish was just gone and not
there. Um, but we would have liked to
see this baby step in that direction,
but it did not make it out um of
committee last um last Friday. Uh this
morning, I do believe that
uh storm water, there's legislation
regarding storm water. That one has
officially been assigned an interim
topic that will be studied by a a
subcommittee over the over the the
summer before the next session. So that
will be back, but it is an interim topic
that storm water legislation essentially
uh said any storm water fee, tax, you
name it. any way you can say money is
going towards a jurisdiction, it would
have required it to be approved by the
voters in
November um or prior to actually it was
prior to any of those fees or taxes or
whatever being being enacted and then it
required that anyone with existing fees
in place like the city of Cheyenne, the
city of Laramie, I believe the city of
Green River is the one who also has it
that they would have had to have a vote
in November of this here um to see if
citizens wanted to continue it. Uh that
bill failed and that's going to go to
continued study. We will see it again.
That discussion is not watered down the
drain. Is continuing to pull up. Uh the
other items that we've been watching
is the what's called the fifth
amendment, the protection of the fifth
amendment, I believe. Uh Seth, have you
seen anything on that recently?
Basically, this is targeted at Jackson
and what it says is that no uh governing
body can essentially require
inclusionary housing. So, a requirement
that
with a commercial or residential
development, you have to pay into a land
bank, a fund or provide um affordable
housing for the community. So, that was
um one that targeted at Jackson. I do
not know how that turned out. I haven't
looked at it recently. The one thing
I've been watching is is it worded in a
way that um
prohibited with industrial development,
which is more of our concern. Not that
we're proposing any of that right now.
I'm just it was a concern. it would that
be off the table and it did not apply to
industrial development.
Um the other final bill is uh House Bill
Two which has a corresponding
Senate file um another Senate one that's
been introduced for concurrence. That
was the first bill filed and is
appropriately deemed the fasttrack
permits bill. It's sponsored by local
representative Lee Filer and that one uh
made it through the House and there was
a concurrent bill that was going through
the Senate and I've been so busy with
other things lately. I've not taken the
last couple of days to see where that
one stands. But I believe it was
introduced believe it was referred to
committee. Oh, it was introduced. It was
referred to committee and it came out of
committee on
last week. I I was at I was at the
hearing. I think it was Thursday
morning. So, it'll probably uh be
finalized and have its last two
readings, well, three readings in front
of the um Senate and that will probably
be be passed. I believe that's all we
were really monitoring. Seth, is there
anything that you can recall
or any other details or things you may
know? We've all been a little bit busy
with other tasks recently that have had
us looking other directions. All
right, that's all I have. Thank you for
the reminder. I should add that to every
agenda during a legislative session.
>> Okay, thank you. Any other questions,
comments, requests for staff
announcements?
Hearing none, I'm still looking for a
motion to adjurnn.
>> I move to adjourn.
Uh,
second.
I guess I don't need a second to a
motion to adjurnn. The meeting is
adjourned.